# 大家好 現在帶大家看一下我們那個小狗哇
Hi everyone! I'm now taking you to have a look at our puppies.
# 長得胖墩墩的
They're now chubby chubby.
# 看一下
Let's have a look.
# 嘿
Hey!
# 不許進哦
Don't come in!
# 你看 這個狗
Look! This puppy,
# 那麼肥啦
is already that fat.
# 現在都
It's already,
# 這個母狗都生了第三胎啦
the third litter of this mother.
# 好靚哦
So beautiful!
# 你很漂亮哦
You're very pretty!
# 你看你的牙齒長了沒有
See if you have any teeth already.
# 牙都還沒長
Not yet.
# 你看 胖不胖
Look! Isn't it fat?
# 圓溜溜的哦
It's round and plumpy,
# 一坨肉
like a piece of meat.
# 誒誒誒誒 別吃那麼快 先給我看一下你
Ay, ay, ay, ay! Don't eat that fast. Let me have a look at you first.
# 哎喲
Ayo
# 你看 它的爪子好利呀 它的爪子
Look! Its claws are really sharp, its claws.
# 抓人的哦
It can scratch.
# 看一下其它的
Have a look at the others.
# 檢查一下你們
Let me check up on you.
# 啊 給 哎 別吃
Ah! Let me, ay! Stop eating!
# 那麼快 (註︰這個不明白)
So fast!
# 等一下 有的是
Just a second! You'll have plenty to eat.
# 捏痛它啦
I hurt it.
# 不好意思哦
I'm sorry.
# 把你錯 把你當成竹鼠啦
I wrong, I wrongly treated you as a bamboo rat.
# 別叫 叫那麼大聲幹嘛 就你最怕
Don't scream! Why are you screaming that loudly? You are the most scared.
# 嗯 又沒碰你 呵呵
Um! I didn't even touch you, hm hm!
# 它就這樣子的
It's so scared.
# 怎麼了你
What happened to you?
# 你媽媽不是在這裡嗎
Isn't your mom right here?
# 額 眼睛要睜開了一點點
Eh? The eyes have opened a bit.
# 它應該還看不到
I think it still can't see.
# 又是公的
It's male again.
# 全是公的
All are male.
# 這條
This one
# 別吃那麼快 別吃那麼快 過來
Don't eat that fast! Don't eat that fast! Come here!
# 誒誒 放掉 放掉
Ey, ey! Drop it! Drop it!
# 咬住 哎呀
It's biting hard. Aya!
# 把你扒過來看一下
Let me turn you over and have a look.
# 不許動
Don't move!
# 雙手舉起來
Hands up!
# 舌頭
Tongue!
# 伸出來
Show me!
# 呵呵 那個舌 小舌頭
Hm hm! The tongue, small tongue,
# 伸出來啦
is coming out.
# 你認不認識我
Do you know me?
# 啊
Ah?
# 現在都圓溜溜 胖墩墩
They're all round and chubby now.
# 耳朵豎起來
The ears are standing.
# 不吃青菜也不吃蘿蔔
You eat neither vegetables, nor radish,
# 就吃奶
but only milk.
# 呵呵
Hm, hm!
# 來來來來來來 快吃奶 吃奶 吃奶
Come, come, come! Eat, eat, eat!
# 真是的
What a puppy!
# 吃飽點啊
Eat more!
# 吃肥一點啊
And get fatter!
# 你看 吃多歡啊
Look! They're eating so merrily.
# 這幾條小狗長大啦
When these puppies grow up,
# 把它帶到那個新的廠地裡面去
I'll bring them to the new site,
# 讓它在那裡
where they can,
# 繁衍生息
breed and enjoy their lives.
# 我們去看一下小豬
Let's take a look at the piglets.
# 小豬現在也胖啦
The piglets are also getting fat now.
# 小豬我來來啦
Piglets! I'm coming!
# 你看 我一進去 它們就想跑
Look! They wanna run away as soon as I come in.
# 我都沒對它們做甚麼
I haven't done anything to them.
# 它就那麼怕我
But they're already that scared of me.
# 這豬是怎麼了
What happened to the pigs?
# 小豬
Piglets!
# 我來看你們啦
I'm coming to visit you!
# 你看 這些豬都是在睡大覺
Look! These pigs are all enjoying a good sleep,
# 曬大陽
and having a sunbath.
# 多爽啊
Cool!
# 那公豬
The boar,
# 最大的公豬躺在那裡
the largest boar is lying there.
# 爽歪歪喲
So cool!
# 是不是
Isn't it?
# 又做老爸啦 是不是
You're a dad again, aren't you?
# 爽歪歪
So cool!
# 死公豬 (註︰怎麼罵人了)
God damned boar!
# 這公豬
This boar...
# 下次還拱不拱我
Will you attack me next time?
# 宰了你幾條豬哦
Now I've killed some of your pigs.
# 宰了你幾條小豬
I've killed some of your piggies.
# 看你還敢不敢拱我啦
Let me see if you still dare to attack me.
# 這兩條小公豬
These two little boars,
# 過年的時候就可以宰了這兩條公的
I can kill these two boars by the Chinese New Year.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 那條最胖的哪裡去啦
Where's the fattest one?
# 好不好玩
Is it fun?
# 額 在這裡 就是你
Eh? Here. It's you.
# 就你最胖是不是
You're the fattest, aren't you?
# 現在你都瘦了哦
But now you're getting skinny.
# 嘿
Hey!
# 好兇啊 那條公豬
It's so fierce, the boar.
# 那麼大 不要去惹
It's so big. I'd better leave it alone.
# 獠牙都長出來啦
It even has tusks coming up.
# 我看到好像有幾個好黃的橘子啊
It seems that there are a few golden yellow tangerines.
# 上去看下
Let me take a look up there.
# 幹嘛
What happened!
# 又不會對你怎麼樣
I won't do any harm on you.
# 你看 這個 好黃啊 這個橘子
Look! This is, golden yellow, this tangerine.
# 這砂糖橘來的
It's a "sugar tangerine".
# 今年好少哇
There are very few this year.
# 好像長都沒長 都長了一兩個
There doesn't seem to be any, except a couple of them.
# 嗯
Um!
# 酸酸甜甜
Sweet and sour
# 這個不能吃啊 都青的
These are not edible. They're still green.
# 搞兩個黃的 吃一下(註︰不太像譯「黃」這個字，很奇怪，避一下)
Let me get a few more.
# 嗯 這裡有一個
Um! Here's one!
# 豬也很喜歡吃橘子的哦
The pigs like tangerines very much too.
# 去年
Last year,
# 兩個條大豬哇
the two big pigs,
# 那時還小
when they were still small,
# 跑到樹上去吃
they climbed onto the trees to eat the tangerines.
# 把樹搞壞幾棵
Several trees were damaged.
# 沒黃的啦
No more?
# 誒
Hai!
# 嗯 這一個
Um! Here's one.
# 還有黃的
One more golden yellow one.
# 來小豬 給你們吃橘子皮
C'mon piggies! Have some tangerine peel!
# 吃了橘子皮的肉很入味的哦
Your pork would be much more flavourful after having the tangerine peel.
# 一定要
We always,
# 煮豬肉都放點橘子皮下去
put some tangerine peel to cook with pork.
# 呵呵
Hm hm!
# 白鼻子的
It's white-nosed.
# 這個 白腳白鼻子的這條小豬哇
This, this white-nosed and white-legged piggy,
# 我還小的時候經常去抱它
I used to snuggle it very often when it was small.
# 不知道還記不記得
I wonder if it can still remember.
# 還記不記我抱過你呀
Do you still remember me snuggling you?
# 抱著你照相的哦
I've taken a picture holding you in my hands.
# 你還好小的時候 你只有那麼大一點點的時候
When you were still very small, you were just as big as this tiny little bit,
# 我抱著你來照相
I've taken a picture with you.
# 沒良心
Heartless!
# 一說它 它就跑到後面去啦
It runs immediately to the back as soon as I talk about it.
# 下次
Next time,
# 下次過年的時候
next time, when the Chinese New Year comes...
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 我要回去煮飯啦
I need to go back to cook,
# 煮飯餵竹鼠
cook for the bamboo rats.